so the fault tolerance
techniques that are used often are
checkpointing where we can save the
state of the system
periodically then we detect errors and
restore the state of the system once we
detect an error this type of technique
works really well for many transient and
also intermittent faults so the idea
here is that we will save the state of
the system when the system is
functioning normally if a fault occurs
we will try to detect errors that result
from that and restore the system into a
state that was not affected by the fault
so if the fault is transient it will not
happen again and our system goes back to
functioning normally if the fault is
intermittent then this might happen a
few times until we reach the time when
the fault is no longer going to be
activated and then again we will
function normally so the system
continues to function normally if we can
quickly recover from each of the faults
so that it doesn't affect the overall
availability and reliability of the
system
if checkpointing takes too long then
this type of recovery has to be treated
as service Interruption but if
checkpointing and detection and
restoring of the state are very very
fast it may be that the promised service
is never disrupted so for example if the
system is supposed to answer all the web
queries within let's say 1 second if we
manage to do all of this in such a way
that we still respond to all of of the
things that we got in one second then
there has been no service Interruption
we can use two-way redundancy where two
modules do the same work then we compare
their results and we roll back if the
results are different so this is really
an error detection technique and it
needs a recovery technique such as
checkpointing similarly checkpointing is
a recovery technique it needs something
like two-way redundancy to actually
detect errors and while these techniques
recover and detect things separately we
can also have something like three-way
redundancy which can both detect and
recover some faults and in this case
three modules or more will do the same
work and then vote for what the correct
result should be so if one module is
malfunctioning then the two others will
still produce the same result and that
result will be elected by the vote as
the overall correct result so the fult
in one module becomes an error in that
module but doesn't become an error at
the system level because at the output
of these three modules and their voter
we always have an error free result this
technique is expensive you pretty much
need three times the hardware plus the
voter that you would have without some
fault tolerance techniques but in return
it can tolerate any fault that can occur
in any one of the modules so as long as
the fault that you have is affecting
only one module we can tolerate that
fault even for example if that one
module is purposely designed to be
malicious cu the correct two are still
going to outvote it and we never really
see whatever that module is trying to
produce in our overall results but what
happens if two modules fail in that case
we no longer can tolerate that